rosneft.com 2014-05-18

# Rosneft - Privacy statement

## Personal information

Personal information is information that can be used to identify you as a specific individual; for example, your name, address, email address or telephone number.  If during your visit you personalise the Site, complete an order form, enter a contest or submit other information to us.  That personal information may be collected and used to provide you with products or services, to bill you for products and services you request, to market products and services to you, or to communicate with you for other purposes ~~~~

Rosneft may appoint third party organisations to assist in providing you with the information, goods, products and services you request.  In these circumstances, steps will be taken to ensure that your personal information is held in strict accordance with our privacy policy and is only used for the purpose of fulfilling your request.  Rosneft does not sell or distribute your personal information to third parties for the purposes of allowing them to market their products and services to you.

Personal data collected by Rosneft may be transferred among its various divisions and affiliated companies around the world, which may involve transfer from countries within the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) to countries outside the EEA.  By submitting data on the Site, the visitor is providing explicit consent to these transfers, including transborder transmission of data covered by this Privacy Statement.

## Automatically collected data

Visitors’ domain and IP address are logged automatically.  This data is not personal information and it does not identify you as an individual, but only the computer that is being used to view the Site.  It is used to see where the Site is being used in the world to ensure coverage, and for click stream analysis to help better understand Site usage.  Rosneft does not link information automatically logged by such means with personal data about specific individuals.

However, personal information might inadvertently be collected due to automatic functions in the third party commercial software used in the operation of Rosneft servers.  If it is discovered that such a collection has taken place then reasonable steps will be taken to remove it from Rosneft’s systems.

## Data retention

Data will be held for the lifetime your subscription is active for the purposes of contacting you effectively after which time it is depersonalised and non-identifiable.  We do not collect any additional information about you other than that outlined above.

## Cookies

Some information (commonly known as a ‘cookie’) may be stored on your computer when you look at or use this Site.  This information facilitates your use of the Site and ensures that you do not need to re-enter your details every time you visit it.  You can erase or block this information from your computer if you want to; your user manual or help files should give instructions on how to do this.

## Opt-out/modification of information

You may request the removal or modification of your personal information by sending an email to the appropriate area under [Contact Us].  Reasonable steps will then be taken to fulfill your request.

## Hyperlinks

This Site may have links to sites that Rosneft does not own, control or maintain.  Rosneft cannot control the privacy policies of such sites and makes no representations or warranties about the privacy policies of such sites.  Similarly, Rosneft cannot be responsible for the policies and practices of any site from which you linked to this Site. 

## Chat rooms, notice boards and newsgroups

If at any time this Site offers any chat rooms, notice board or forum facilities, newsgroups, etc., any information that you disclose thereon may be collected and used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  Rosneft cannot be responsible for other parties’ use of any information which you make available to such third parties through any chat room, notice board, newsgroup etc on this Site. 

## Security

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control that complies fully with data privacy and protection legislation appropriate to the jurisdiction applicable to the Site.  The security measures are designed to prevent access, improper use or disclosure, modification and unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

At present we do not give visitors to our Site the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data.

## Children

This Site is neither directed nor targeted to children. Rosneft will not knowingly collect information from children.  However, the software used to operate this Site does not automatically distinguish visitors under 18 from other visitors, so Rosneft requires users under 18 years of age to obtain the consent of a parent, guardian, teacher or librarian to view this Site.  If Rosneft discovers that a child has provided personal information to this Site, it will take reasonable steps to remove such information from its files. 

## Conditions of use, notices and revisions

If you choose to visit this Site, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and the General Terms set out above. Rosneft reserves the right to change this policy without notice.  Your continued use of this Site following the posting of changes to this policy constitutes your acceptance of such changes.
